The FBI are about to discover that things work a little differently around here.
The Guard is a action, comedy, thriller film directed by John Michael McDonagh.
When a small-town Irish cop with a crass personality is partnered with a straight-laced FBI agent to bust an
international drug-trafficking ring, they must settle their differences in order to take down a dangerous gang.
Sergeant Gerry Boyle, played by Brendan Gleeson.
FBI agent Wendell Everett, played by Don Cheadle.
Francis Sheehy, played by Liam Cunningham.
Clive Cornell, played by Mark Strong.
Gabriela McBride, played by Katarina Čas.
Liam O'Leary, played by David Wilmot.
The Guard is a 2011 buddy cop comedy film written and directed by John Michael McDonagh,
starring Brendan Gleeson, Don Cheadle, Mark Strong and Liam Cunningham.
The film received critical acclaim and was a box office success.
Both Gleeson and Cheadle received acclaim for their performances,
with Gleeson receiving a Golden Globe Award nomination.
McDonagh was in turn nominated for a BAFTA Award for his writing achievement.
It is the most successful independent Irish film of all time in terms of Irish
box-office receipts, overtaking The Wind that Shakes the Barley (2006).
The film explores themes of prostitute, drug
smuggling, blackmail, rural area, ireland.
The tone is lighthearted and intense.